Andrea Estefanía Castellanos Suárez

Full-Stack Jr. Developer. | Frontend

andreaecastellanossuarez@gmail.com | +528446062257 | Saltillo, Coahuila. México | <u>Andrea Castellanos</u> | <u>ACas96</u> | Willing to relocate

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Full-stack Jr. developer with experience in frontend and backend design using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, which allows me to create comprehensive and user-centered solutions. I am a self-taught professional who is always in continuous learning. My passion for design and innovation drives me to always stay updated with the aim of continuing to grow professionally.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: | Python | CSS | HTML | FIGMA | Bootstrap | REACT | JavaScript | Java | MySQL Workbench | Git | Arduino | SolidWorks | Catia | Ansys Workbench

Soft Skills: Detail orientation | Leadership | Teamwork | Proactivity | Organization and punctuality | Assertive communication | Sense of urgency | Growth orientation | Active listening.

EXPERIENCE

Saihon | (Certification project), Generation México

05/2024- 07/2024

- Collaborative e-commerce focused on the sale of books developed with various tools and programming languages. HTML, CSS, Figma, JavaScript were used for the frontend. For the backend, Java and Spting Boot were implemented. Finally, the application was deployed on an AWS server.
- I proposed the color palette for the project and actively participated in the development of forms and the design and adjustment of the frontend.
- I played the role of Product Owner and Scrum Master in the early stages of the Project

Proviem Prosthetist | Monterrey, N. L.

04/2023-07/20

- I supported the development of external lower limb prostheses for ampute patients.
- I provided care and support in the process of adaptation to a prosthesis.

Rogelio Bicicletas Branch Manager | Saltillo, Coahuila

11/2022-04/2023

- I coordinated a work team to ensure the proper functioning of the store and customer service.
- I organized and supervised activities for inventory control and management.
- I managed the receipt of merchandise by dealing directly with suppliers.
- Supported store management with different administrative issues.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

CineMix. | Generation México

05/2024

• Local cinema online page. I developed and implemented the HTML and CSS design for the "candy shop" and "contact us" pages using CSS and Boostrap, giving it an original and responsive design.

EDUCATION

Certificates

- Java Full-Stack Developer | Generation Mexico | April 2024 July 2024 | Intensive bootcamp of +500 hrs focused on the development of technical Java skills and soft skills.
- Diploma in Automation Training | Ingelearn | March 2024 | Online course focused on the programming of electronic automation boards.
- Python Programming | Udemy | November 2022 | Basic programming course in the Python language.

University

• **Bionic Engineer,** *Universidad Popular Autónoma del Estado de Puebla (UPAEP)*08/2016-07/2022

Integration of biology and technology to design medical devices, prosthetics, and rehabilitation systems that enhance quality of life.

LANGUAGES

English B2 Spanish (native)